Guide to the Virgil Keeble Whitaker Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Virgil Keeble Whitaker papers
1945-1973
SC0174
Whitaker, Virgil Keeble, 1908-
3 Linear feet (2 boxes)
Professor Whitaker's office files contain primarily Stanford material relating to his years as Professor of English, his membership on various university committees and professional interests. Includes correspondence, minutes and general material relating to Whitaker's career.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Virgil Whitaker, 1974.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of English at Stanford (1934-1967; emeritus 1974-1984 ); Associate Provost; and Dean of the Graduate Division (1965-1969).
Description of the Collection
Professor Whitaker's office files contain primarily Stanford material relating to his years as Professor of English, his membership on various university committees and professional interests. Includes correspondence, minutes and general material relating to Whitaker's career.
Arrangement
The material is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Dean of Graduate Studies.; Stanford University. Department of English. Faculty.; Stanford University. Department of English. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Whitaker, Virgil Keeble, 1908-
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1945-1973; Original Accession
  - Advisory Board, 1953-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A.A.U.P. (American Association of University Professors), 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Studies Group, 1945-1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Articles of Organization of the Faculty, 1951-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bacon Foundation, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Committees, miscellaneous, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Composition Teaching Study, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Enrollment Policies, Comm. on, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Executive Comm., Academic Council, 1953-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Minutes.
  - Executive Comm. of Humanties & Sciences, 1953-1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Financial Awards, Committee on, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Foreign Centers Search Committee, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Freshman Composition - Student Opinion, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - General Studies, Committee on, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General Studies, Committee on - Subcommittee on Italian Study Center, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Graduate Study Committee, 1953-1957 (Folder 18)
  - Graduate Study Committee, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Graduate Study Committee, Subcommittee on "Applications for Candidacy for Master of Arts", 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Graduate Study Committee, Subcommittee on Policies, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Humanities & Sciences, miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Humanities, Graduate Program in - Subcommittee, 1954-1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Humanities Conference, 1946 May 23-26 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Humanities - Honors Program, Committee on, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Humanities, Ph.D. in, Program Committee, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Humanities, Ph.D. in, Santa Barbara meeting, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Humanities - Special Programs, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Independent Study Committee, 1945, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Lectures - Western Civ., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Liberal Arts Program at Stanford, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Library Conference, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - MLA (Modern Language Assn.), Eng. V, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - MLA - General, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - MLA - Meeting, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - MLA - Meeting, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - MLA - Shakespeare Section, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - MLA - Shakespeare Section, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - MLA - Spenser Section, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1952-1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, Univ. of Oregon, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Philological Association of the Pacific Coast, 1951-1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Philological Association of Stanford, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Public Exercises, Committee on, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Public Exercises - Founders Day, Subcommittee on, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Publications Committee, 1951-1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Schedules & Exams, Comm. on, 1946, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Senior Colloquia, Comm. on, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Shakespeare Quarterly, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Stanford in Britain, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Stanford in Britain, Subcommittee on, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Stanford in Italy, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Study of Undergraduate Education, Advisory Committee (2 folders), 1954-1956 (Box 2)
  - Student-Faculty Educational Policies Cornrnission, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Summer Festivals, Comm. on, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Supplementary Research Grants, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Undergraduate Curriculum, Committee on, ''Meditations on the difference between training and education," prepared by F.W. Strothmann, 1954 Nov 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Undergraduate Library Committee, 1957-1963 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Undcrgraduate Library Committee, pamphlets, 1957, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - University Testing Program Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Viking Fund Grant, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Viking Fund Grant - Humanities-Anthropology Conference, 1947 May 16-17 (Box 2, Folder 24)